# Rances Rodriguez

<u>rances.rodriguez@gmail.com</u> • (925) 565 0082 • Oakland • GitHub: <u>https://github.com/Caliza</u> • <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/rances-rodriguez/</u>

# Summary

Software Engineer leveraging background in Commercial HVAC with more than 8 years of experience in pursuit of a career change. Earned a certificate in Full Stack Web Development from UC Berkeley Extension Bootcamp. Enthusiastic, great communication, and interpersonal skills; motivated to keep growing in software development and programming. Works well in teams and adaptable with great communication and interpersonal skills and natural problem solving.

# **Key Skills**

- HTML
- CSS
- Javascript
- React.js
- Responsive Design
- Bootstrap
- REST API & API
- GraphQL

- jQuery
- Bulma
- MVS
- Node.js
- Express.js
- My SQL & Sequelize
- MongoDB & Mongoose
- Apollo

# **Projects**

- Movie Reviewer: https://github.com/JordyMarquez/Binary-Trio-Movie-Reviewer
- Heroku: <a href="https://binary-trio-movie-reviewer.herokuapp.com/">https://binary-trio-movie-reviewer.herokuapp.com/</a>
- Tools: React.js JS Library, CSS, Semantic HTML5 markup, Next.js, Styled Components
- React Portfolio: <a href="https://github.com/Caliza/reactPortfolio">https://github.com/Caliza/reactPortfolio</a>
- Deployed App: https://caliza.github.io/reactPortfolio/
- Tools: React.js JS Library, CSS, Semantic HTML5 markup

# **Professional Experience**

# **ACCO Engineered Systems**

### **HVAC Journeyman**

San Leandro, CA, August 2019 - January 2023

- Specialized in commercial installation of air conditioning and heating systems.
- Worked in teams of 2-3 people and independently to accomplish tasks on schedule and collaborated with other contractors to resolve trade conflicts and complete projects.
- Managed a team of 6 people at renovation of Meta Headquarters, Menlo Park, CA distributing and overseeing completion of assignments.
- Built clean rooms at SLAC National Accelerator Laboratory, pharmaceutical laboratories at AbbVie Pharmaceutical, and modern office space for Google, Facebook, Adobe, and various tech companies implementing LEAD construction practices.
- Pressure tested sections of air duct with AirXpress MTC equipment for air leakage to ensure duct systems were within allowable CFM loss according to spec.
- Read blueprints to do layout, scale, measure, mark dimensions and reference lines on floor for wall penetrations, support hangers, and duct ceiling path.

• Installed and fabricated ductwork, VAV boxes, Fire-Smoke dampers using hand and power tools following Fire and Life Safety regulations.

# Southland Industries HVAC Apprentice

Union City, CA, July 2017 - August 2019

- Specialized in commercial installation of air conditioning and heating systems.
- Worked in teams of 2-3 people and independently to accomplish tasks on schedule and collaborated with other contractors to resolve trade conflicts and complete projects.
- Worked on large hospital projects such as UCSF Precision Cancer Medical Building and Sutter Health Van Ness installing ductwork, flex duct, ceiling and wall registers, VAV boxes, Fire-Smoke dampers using hand and power tools following OSHPD and Fire and Life Safety regulations.

#### **Control Air**

### **HVAC Apprentice**

Hayward, CA, August 2016 - July 2017

- Shop work doing sheet metal fabrication.
- Worked in round department building fittings such as square-to-round, Y-branches, conical reducers, round elbows (45° and 90°).
- Operated spot-welders, rollers, plasma table, and pneumatic shears.
- Worked with heavy gauge metal, tac-welded pieces together in preparation for welding (galvanized and stainless steel).
- Insulated fittings and prefabrication of duct sections at shop in preparation for transportation to field site.

#### **NV Heathorn**

# **HVAC Apprentice**

San Leandro, CA, August 2014 - July 2016

- Worked on architectural installations such as aluminum panels, gutters, flashings, scuppers, etc.
- Renovation of ductwork and installation of new HEPA filters for every room in Post-op/Bone Marrow transplant at UCSF Parnassus.

### **Private Tutor**

Contra Costa County, CA, 2004 - 2014

- Aimed to find students' areas of struggle and support students (tutees) to become more independent learners, persist in school, and reach their goals.
- Tutored Mathematics and Spanish to elementary, middle, and high school kids.
- Spanish lessons covered Elementary, Intermediate, and Advanced Spanish.
- Math tutoring ranged from Elementary Algebra to Calculus.
- Assisted students in homework and trouble areas to improve their comprehension and understanding of materials.
- Tutoring sessions were performed one-on-one and occasionally in small groups.

# **Education**

**UC Berkeley Extension,** Berkeley, CA, May 2023 **Certificate** Full Stack Web Development

**UC Berkeley,** Berkeley, CA, 2007-2010 **Bachelors of Arts** in Spanish and Portuguese